快点  不然会被他们杀死的
快点
你还有奶水吗
你们要去哪里
他们要见她
先生  就是她
Sir? This is her.
会算命的小女孩
The girl who tells fortunes?
他们在施魔法  让那匹马赢得比赛
They're doing a magic spell to make her win a race.
我的宝马名叫摩纳根小子
The horse's name's Monaghan Boy.
坎普敦赛马场  周一  3点
Kempton, three o'clock, Monday.
你们可以下注押它  但不要告诉别人
You ladies have a bet yourselves but don't tell anyone else.
英格兰伯明翰  1919年
"亚伯拉罕居于山洞
"And Abraham made his home in a cave,
但那没关系
"but it was good
因为主与他同在
"because God resided there with him.
上帝的儿女们  主并不在乎
"You see, children, God does not care
你是住在贫民窟还是豪宅
"if you live in a slum or in a mansion.
主并不在乎你是贫穷还是富有
"God does not care if you are rich or you are poor.
你们都是主的..."
"You are still God's..."
早上好  先生
Morning, sir.
早上好  谢尔比先生
Morning, Mr. Shelby.
浴   血
黑   帮
第一季   『人人影视英剧社倾情奉献』   第一集
-快点  伙计  -早  先生
- Come on, lad. - Morning, sir.
-早  谢尔比先生  -快点
- Morning, Mr. Shelby. - Come on, hurry up!
芬恩
Finn?
亚瑟气得要死
Arthur's mad as hell.
一个10岁的小孩懂什么生死啊
What does a ten-year-old know about hell, eh?
我周日就11岁了
I'm 11 Sunday.
坎普敦下午2:30的赛马开始下注
Place your bets here now for the 2:30 at Kempton.
改成一赔四
Down to fours...
好了  女士们先生们  快来试试运气
OK, girls and boys, you want to push that now, mate.
非常感谢
Thanks very much.
一赔二  速速下注
2-1, get your bets in now.
想选哪匹  可以押"帝王"
What d'you say? We've got Sovereign,
它是老热门了  一赔四
he's an old favourite, 4-1.
汤米  汤米
Tommy. Tommy!
汤米  看看账本  你看
Tommy, look at the book. Just look.
-汤米  -全都押摩纳根小子
- Tommy! - All on Monaghan Boy.
好样的  约翰
Good work, John.
汤米  立刻进来
Tommy! Get in here, now!
六便士  小伙
That'll be six pennies, Nipper.
十先令  等着稳赚吧
That's ten bob you'll see for that.
有人看到你在加里森巷玩红粉巫术
You was seen doing the powder trick down at Garrison Court.
时下境况艰难
Times are hard.
人们需要一个下注的理由
People need a reason to lay a bet.
听说还有个中国人
There was a Chinese.
洗衣女说她是个巫女
The washer women say she's a witch.
他们比较迷信这种事
It helps them believe.
我们不能招惹中国人
We don't mess with Chinese.
看看账本
Look at the book...
中国人有他们自己的地盘
Chinese have cutters of their own.
我们商量好了的  亚瑟
We agreed, Arthur.
我负责招揽新生意
I'm taking charge of drumming up new money.
万一摩纳根小子赢了怎么办  汤米
What if Monaghan Boy wins, Tommy?
你现在还操纵比赛了吗
You fixing races now?
你有没有取得比利·肯波的许可
Do you have permission from Billy Kimber to be fixing races, hm?
你脑子进水了吗
Then what's got into you?
你认为我们能同时对付
You think we can take on
中国人和比利·肯波吗
the Chinese and Billy Kimber.
比利他妈的有一支军队
Billy's got a bloody army!
我会用脑子想  亚瑟
I think... Arthur.
我就是靠脑子的
That's what I do.
我会动脑子
I think...
那样你就不用动脑子了
so that you don't have to.
贝尔法斯特那边传来一条消息
There's news from Belfast.
一赔十变一赔八
Down from tens over eights...
我今晚8点要召开家族会议
I'm calling a family council tonight at eight o'clock.
我要求所有人都到场
I want all of us there.
听见了吗  我们有麻烦了
You hear me?! There's trouble coming.
最高机密  政治保安处
伯明翰轻兵器公司军火劫案头号嫌犯
亚瑟·谢尔比  沃特里巷6号
黑帮成员  敲诈  非法赌马
剃刀党
剃刀党首领
汤米·谢尔比  沃特里巷6号
敲诈  收取保护费  持枪抢劫
剃刀党
因英勇表现获国王勋章
好了  闭嘴吧  安静
All right, shut up now. Shut up.
同志们
Comrades...
-我们今天将投票决定是否罢工  -太棒了
- we're here today to take a vote on strike action. - Yes!
但在举手表决前
But before we have a show of hands for that...
先请在法国战斗过的同胞举一下手
let's have a show of hands from all those who fought in France,
你们与同志们并肩作战
all those who stood side-by-side with your comrades
亲眼目睹他们牺牲  举起你们的手
and watched your comrades fall. Raise your hands.
多少鲜血洒在了佛兰德斯
The blood shed on Flanders fields,
你们流了多少汗
the sweat of your brows!
而谁盗取了胜利的果实
Who reaps the rewards?
是你们吗
Is it you?
不是
No.
是你们的妻子吗
Is it your wives?
不是
No!
-那么是谁呢  他们在场吗  -不在
- Who, then? Do they stand among us? - No!
他们安逸地坐在家里  脑满肠肥
Or do they sit at home, comfortable, with a full belly
而你们却辛苦劳作
while you scrape to find
只为自己的孩子能吃饱穿暖
enough to put shoes on your children's feet!
-没错  -他们是怎样
- Yes! - And what is the reward
回报你们的牺牲呢
they offer you for your sacrifices made?
狗日的降薪
A fucking cut in your wages!
那就是你们得到的回报
That is your reward!
想要罢工的人  举起手来
Raise a hand, all those who want to strike!
弗莱迪·索恩  南街26号
伯明翰轻兵器工厂工会领导人
共产主义煽动者  布尔什维克主义者
汤米·谢尔比的朋友
免费赠送一杯  谢尔比先生
On the house, Mr. Shelby.
-给我来一杯淡啤  -好
- I'll take a mild. - Right.
干杯  汤玛斯
Cheers, Thomas.
祝你康健
Good health to you.
王子的王冠
The crown of a prince.
-我赌你不久就能当上国王  -你不赌博
- Soon to be King, I'd bet. - You don't bet.
的确  近来几天来我一直在思考
No, but these past few days I've been speculating.
思考什么
About what?
我一位工会的同志有个姐妹
One of my Union comrades has a sister,
她在伯明翰轻兵器工厂的电报局工作
works in the telegraph office at the BSA factory.
她说这几周她们收到了多封
She says over the past week they've had messages
温斯顿·丘吉尔亲自从伦敦发给高层的电报
coming up from London to the brass from Winston Churchill himself.
是关于一起劫案的
Something about a robbery.
上面说是"举国震惊的劫案"
"A robbery of national significance", it said.
她在电报机上发现了一个名单
She found the list of names left on the telegraph machine.
那上面有你和我的名字
And on that list was your name and my name together.
什么样的名单上
What kind of a list would have the name
会同时有共产党和赌马徒的名字
of a Communist and the name of a bookmaker side-by-side?
也许上面写的都是给穷人虚假希望的人
Perhaps it's a list of men who give false hope to the poor.
弗莱迪  你和我之间唯一的区别
The only difference between you and me, Freddie,
就是有时
is that sometimes...
我的马还有可能赢
my horses stand a chance of winning.
有时我听到那些
You know, there are days
砍人和毒打的恶行
when I hear about the cuttings and beatings
我真希望你在法国挨那一枪
that I really wish I'd let you take that bullet in France.
相信我  有时深夜里我也这么希望
Believe me, there are nights I wish you had.
-他们会杀了我  -数到三  三二一  摁倒
- They're going to get me! - On three. One, two, three, down!
深呼吸  丹尼  深呼吸
Breathe, Danny, breathe!
他们会杀了我
They're going to kill me!
-丹尼  -丹尼
- Danny!  - Danny!
丹尼  你回家了  我们都在英国
Danny, you're home. We're all home in England.
你不在法国
You're not in France.
你不是一枚炮弹  丹尼  你是个人
You're not an artillery shell, Danny, you're a man. Eh?
你不是高速炮弹
You're not a whizz bang.
你是人  丹尼
You're a human being, Danny.
没事了  你已经没事了  没事了
You're all right, you're all right, you're all right.
起来  起来
Up! Up!
没事了  放轻松
It's all right, it's all right.
该死  我又犯毛病了吗
Oh, hell. Did I do it again?
你又犯毛病了  丹尼
You did it again, Danny.
你不能再这样了  伙计
Got to stop doing this, man.
-没事的  -天啊  谢尔比先生
- It's all right. - Oh, God, Mr. Shelby,
我很抱歉
I'm sorry...
没事的  回家陪老婆去吧  丹尼
It's all right. You go home to your wife now, Danny.
别再想那些战场上的事情了
Try and get all that smoke and mud out of your head, eh?
是  谢尔比先生  我很抱歉
Yes, Mr. Shelby. I'm sorry.
走吧
Go on.
谢尔比先生  你得对他采取点措施了
Mr. Shelby, you have to do something about him.
说的太对了  哈里
Damn right, Harry.
你给剃刀党付了那么多保护费
You pay the Peaky Blinders a lot of money for protection.
你就是这里的法律  汤米  对吗
You're the law around here now, Tommy, aren't you?
或许你该一枪崩了丹尼
Maybe you should put a bullet in Danny Whizz Bang's head
就像他们对待疯马那样
like they do with mad horses.
说不定哪天你也得一枪崩了我呢
Maybe you'll have to put a bullet in my head someday, too.
把账单送到剃刀党  我们会结清的
Bring the bill to the Peaky Blinders. We'll take care of this.
看看这把枪
Look at the gun.
认出来了吗
Recognise it?
快点给我站起来  你个蠢猪
Get up off your arse, you mumping pig!
波莉阿姨  你他妈这是干什么
Aunt Pol! What the fuck d'you do that for?!
今天下午芬恩在切割机旁边玩这把枪
Finn was playing with this this afternoon by the cutter.
枪当时是上了膛的
It was loaded.
他差点把艾达的胸膛打烂了
He nearly blew Ada's tits off.
肯定是从我兜里掉出来了
It must've fell out of my pocket.
他说他是在赛马投注站的餐柜上发现的
He said he found it on the sideboard of the betting shop...
而且还装了子弹
with bullets in it.
那估计我当时是喝高了
Ma... I must've been drunk.
你什么时候清醒过
When are you not drunk?
波莉阿姨  我很抱歉
Look, Aunt Pol, I'm sorry.
我  我很抱歉
I'm... I'm sorry.
我可以不把这事告诉任何人
We'll keep this between ourselves
前提是你发誓以后不再把枪随处乱放
if you swear not to leave guns lying around.
我知道你独自抚养4个孩子很难
Look, I know having four kids without a woman is hard.
但我也不轻松  快走吧  要迟到了
But my boot's harder. Now, come on, we're late.
好了
Right,
我召集大家来开家族会议
I've called this family meeting
是因为我有重要的事要宣布
because I've got some very important news.
斯卡德伯特和拉夫洛克
Scudboat and Lovelock
昨晚从贝尔法斯特回来了
got back from Belfast last night.
他们买了匹种马来为母马配种
They were buying a stallion to cover their mares.
昨天他们去了夏克尔路上的一家酒吧
They were in a pub on the Shankhill Road yesterday,
结果那家酒吧里有个警察
and in that pub, there was a copper...
正在发这个
handing out these.
"如果你身高超过5英尺  能打架
"If you're over five feet and can fight,
快来伯明翰吧"
come to Birmingham."
他们正在召集新教徒爱尔兰人
They're recruiting Protestant Irishmen
作为特派员来到这里
to come over here as Specials.
-来干什么  -来清理这座城市  艾达
- To do what? - To clean up the city, Ada.
他是总督察
He's a Chief Inspector.
在过去4年里
The last four years,
他一直在贝尔法斯特清理爱尔兰共和军
he's been clearing the IRA out of Belfast.
你怎么知道这么多情况
How do you know so bloody much?
因为我问过被我们收买的警察
Cos I asked the coppers on our payroll.
那你为什么不告诉我
And why didn't you tell me?
我不是正在告诉你吗
I'm telling you.
那为什么要派他来伯明翰
So why are they sending him to Birmingham?
因为伯明翰轻兵器工厂一直有罢工的情况出现
There's been all these bloody strikes at the BSA...
包括奥斯丁汽车公司
and the Austin works lately.
现在报纸上满版都在谈论暴乱
Now the papers are talking about sedition.
和革命
And revolution.
我猜他是要对共产主义分子下手
I reckon it's Communists he's after.
那这个警察是不会来找我们麻烦的  对吧
So this copper's going to leave us alone, right?
格陵兰大道那边有很多爱尔兰人
There are Irishmen in Green Lanes
是为了躲避他而离开贝尔法斯特的
who left Belfast to get away from him.
他们说有些跟他作对的天主教徒
They say Catholic men who crossed him
到了晚上人就从世上消失了
used to disappear in the night.
是  但我们不是爱尔兰共和军
Yeah, but we ain't IRA.
我们曾经为国王卖命打过仗
We bloody fought for the King.
不管怎样  我们是剃刀党
Anyway, we're Peaky Blinders.
我们才不会怕什么警察
We're not scared of coppers.
-他说的没错  -如果他们来找我们的麻烦
- He's right. - If they come for us,
我们就把他们的脸割开
we'll cut them a smile each.
那亚瑟
So, Arthur...
-就这样吗  -你怎么想  波莉阿姨
- is that it? - What do you think, Aunt Pol?
我们家族做事从不遮遮掩掩
This family does everything open.
你还有别的要在会上说吗  汤玛斯
You've nothing more to say to this meeting, Thomas?
没了
No.
没有女人什么事
Nothing that's women's business.
你们男人出去打仗的时候
This whole bloody enterprise was women's business
整个黑帮帝国都是靠女人来维系的
while you boys were away at war.
现在有什么变了吗
What's changed?
我们回来了
We came back.
而在最后审判日来临时  上帝会惩罚恶徒
And the Lord will smite the unholy when the great judgment comes.
而审判即将来临  朋友们
And judgment is coming, my friends.
审判即将降临于这座邪恶之城
Judgment is coming to this wicked city.
而你们那堕落淫乱的行为终将暴露
And your wickedness and your fornication will be revealed.
你们在造物主面前将无所遁形
You cannot hide from the Creator.
你们在神面前将无处躲藏
You cannot hide from the Almighty himself.
造物主能洞悉一切
The Creator sees all.
你们在真主面前将无法遮掩
You cannot hide from the true and living God...
你给我下来
Get off with yer!
滚远点
Fuck off!
就到这了  我不会再往前开了
That's it, I don't go any further.
我只有十分钟时间  你想怎么样
I have ten minutes. What do you want?
一个解释
An explanation.
我总是能察觉出你对我有所隐瞒
I've always been able to tell when you're hiding something.
周围的人都喜欢蜚短流长
People round here talk.
有人在伯明翰轻武器工厂工作
Some of them work at the BSA.
我和工人的老婆们聊过天
I've been talking to the wives of factory hands.
警探曾去打样车间里问过话
Detectives have been asking questions in the proofing shops.
那家工厂里的所有事都逃不过你的眼睛
Nothing happens in that factory without you knowing about it.
快说
Speak.
上帝和波莉阿姨等着听呢
God and Aunt Polly are listening.
本应该是很平常的事
It was meant to be routine.
我有一位伦敦的买家想买几辆摩托车
I had a buyer in London for some... motorcycles.
我就让我的手下去偷
I asked my men to steal me
4辆带汽油发动机的摩托车
four bikes with petrol engines.
我猜他们当时都喝高了
I'm guessing my men were drunk.
工厂里有个蒸馏室  可以制作杜松子酒
There's a still inside the factory makes tram-line gin.
那帮该死的家伙搬错箱子了
They picked up the wrong fucking crate.
他们按原定计划把箱子
The boys dropped it at
放在了查理·斯特朗家的院子里
Charlie Strong's yard as agreed.
他们肯定是从打样车间偷出来的
They must've taken it from the proofing bay
而不是从出口车间
instead of the export bay.
我的亲娘啊
Holy sweet baby of Mary!
我们在箱子里发现25挺刘易斯机枪
Inside we found 25 Lewis machine guns,
10000盒弹药
10,000 rounds of ammunition,
50把半自动步枪
50 semi-automatic rifles,
200把已装填子弹的手枪
200 pistols with shells.
天啊  汤米
Jesus, Tommy!
本是要送往利比亚的
All bound for Libya.
结果却到了查理·斯特朗家的院子里
Sitting right there in Charlie Strong's yard.
告诉我你把那些扔进切割机处理掉了
Tell me you threw them in the cutter.
我们把它们存放在马厩里了  以防淋雨
We put 'em in the stables, out of the rain.
那些枪还没上过油
The guns hadn't been greased yet.
所以他们才会从贝尔法斯特派警察过来
So that's why they sent a copper from Belfast.
或许是  或许不是
Maybe, maybe not.
汤玛斯  你经营赌马公司
Thomas, you're a bookmaker,
是个强盗  打手
a robber, a fighting man,
但你不傻
you're not a fool.
你敢把枪卖给任何一个能发挥其用武之地的人
You sell those guns to anyone who has use to 'em,
你就死定了
you will hang!
把它们扔到警察能找到的地方
Dump them somewhere the police can find them.
或许他们发现枪没被不该拿的人拿到
Maybe if they know they haven't fallen into the wrong hands
此事就能平息了
this might blow over.
让查理今晚就扔掉
Tell Charlie to dump them tonight.
不行  他从不在月圆之夜动违禁品
No. He won't move contraband under a full moon.
得等上3天  月缺之后
Three days until it wanes.
到时你知道该怎么做吧
Then you'll do the right thing?
你继承了你母亲的理智
You have your mother's common sense,
却也继承了你父亲的邪恶
but your father's devilment.
我可以看到二者的激烈交锋
I see them fighting.
让你母亲的品性获胜吧
Let your mother win.
我拿到了佩妮俱乐部的票
I got tickets for the Penny Crush.
今晚要放映汤姆·米克斯的电影[美国演员]
They're showing a Tom Mix picture.
我今晚可没心情看电影  艾达
I'm not in the mood for the pictures tonight, Ada.
我可不想再在这里做了
Well, I'm not doing it here again.
我上次被淤泥弄得脏兮兮的
I got covered in mud last time.
我们去散散步吧
Let's just walk a bit.
如果走到格雷特街  我们可以去趟酒吧
If we go down as far as Greet, we could go to a pub.
你的兄弟们在格雷特街有朋友啊
Your brothers have friends in Greet.
他们到处都有朋友  我们得走到伦敦才行啊
They have friends everywhere. We'd have to walk to London.
我跟你在一起
I'm with you
因为你是这里唯一不怕他们的男人
because you're the only man round here not scared of them.
我很怕他们的
Oh, I'm scared of them all right.
但你对我的爱胜过对他们的恐惧  对吧
But you love me more than you fear them, right?
我不想老是偷偷摸摸的
I don't want to be always sneaking about.
-快了  我们会告诉他们的  -什么时候
- Soon, we'll tell them. - When?
家族会议开得怎么样
How did the family meeting go?
-老样子  最近新来了个警察  -我听说了
- Usual. There's a new copper coming. - I heard.
汤米说他要抓你们这一类人
And Tommy says he's after the likes of you.
所以也许你该把你的书烧了  别再搞什么演讲了
So maybe you should burn your books and stop making speeches.
我的艾达
Oh, my Ada.
小希斯王国皇室里唯一的公主
The only princess of the royal family of the Kingdom of Small Heath.
我只是个多嘴的共产主义穷小子
I'm just a poor communist frog with a big mouth.
赐我个吻吧  艾达公主
Give me a kiss, Princess Ada.
我是来应聘酒吧女侍的
I'm here about the job as a barmaid.
-你疯了吗  -我怎么了
- Are you mad? - Am I what?
-你知道这是什么地方吗  -我在广告上看到的
- Do you know about this place? - I saw it in an advertisement.
-人已经找到了  -昨天的报纸上才登的广告
- Job's been filled. - It was in yesterday's paper.
相信我  亲爱的  我这是在帮你
Believe me, love, I'm doing you a favour.
我不需要你帮忙  我只需要份工作
I'm not asking for favours. I'm asking for employment.
你太...正派了
You're too... nice.
-你怎么知道  -也太漂亮了
- How would you know? - And too pretty.
他们会把你按在墙上狠干一番的
They'd have you up against a wall.
我有经验  也有介绍信
I have experience and references.
你来自爱尔兰哪里
What part of Ireland are you from?
戈尔韦
Galway.
我以前在都柏林工作
I worked in Dublin.
我母亲来自戈尔韦
Me mother was from Galway.
你还是太漂亮了
You're too pretty.
看着
Watch.
认真听
And listen.
*多希望能回到卡里克弗格斯*
*I wish I was in Carrickfergus*
*只为在巴利格兰的那些夜晚*
*Only for nights in Ballygrand*
*我愿游过深不见底的大海*
*I would swim over the deepest ocean*
*寻找我的心之所爱*
*The deepest ocean my love to find*
*我年少时的友人和亲人*
*My boyhood friends and my own relations*
*都已渐渐离我而去*
*Have all passed on now*
*如白雪消融不见*
*Like the melting snow*
在爱尔兰
In Ireland
我的歌声让人动容落泪  停止打斗
my singing made them cry and stopped them fighting.
希望你会唱很多歌
Well, I hope you know a lot of songs.
婴儿
Babies...
被丢弃在鱼骨蛋壳之间
discarded... with the fish bones and eggshells.
小姑娘们  才11岁
Girls, 11 years old...
老男人花三便士就能随意糟蹋她们
pierced and punctured by old men for thruppence a time!
像禽兽那样发泄欲望
Rutted upon like animals!
堕落
Degradation.
父亲搞上女儿
Fathers with their daughters,
兄弟与姐妹同床共枕
brothers and sisters sharing beds.
大街上满是乞丐和窃贼
Beggars and thieves left to run in the streets.
街两旁却堆满了伤员
And astride the whole stinking pile
伤口腐烂  散发恶臭
of wounds and rotten flesh...
你们的雇主
Your masters!
你们举手致敬的那些家伙
The men who you touch your cap to.
剃刀党
The Peaky Blinders!
邪恶  残忍的黑帮
The vicious... merciless gangs
他们刺瞎原本明亮的眼睛
who blind those that see
割下那些多嘴之人的舌头
and cut out the tongues of those who talk.
你们比他们更卑劣
You are worse than them!
你们之中有人
Those of you who have
自战争爆发就一直在收受他们的贿赂
taken their bribes these years since the war,
有人故意视而不见
those of you who look the other way,
你们  比他们更卑劣
you... are worse than them!
上帝谴责你们玷污了身上的警服
God damn you for soiling your uniforms!
现在又多了爱尔兰共和军的芬尼亚运动会成员
And then... there are the IRA Fenians
以及共产主义分子
and the Communists.
他们的心更加黑暗
Blacker hearts still.
他们依靠这些腐败求生
They feed on the puss of all this corruption
如同死尸上的蛆虫一般
like maggots in a corpse.
如果任由蛆虫成长壮大
And like maggots, if left to swell
那就最终会变成成群的苍蝇
they will eventually swarm like flies
将他们腐烂的思想
and spread their rotten philosophy
传遍全国  传向世界
across the country and across the world!
如此一来  他们便是我们的敌人
Those then... are our enemies!
一个三头巨怪
A three-headed beast.
我的任务就是  对他们斩草除根
It is my job to decapitate each one
我向上帝发誓我一定会做到的
and by God I will do it!
我不信任你们中的任何一人
I don't trust any of yous
除非你们赢得我的信任
until you earn my trust!
那可需要一些努力才行
And that takes some earning.
这些是要加入你们队伍的新人
These are the new men who will bolster your ranks.
都是好人
Good men...
来自虔诚的教徒家庭
from God-fearing families.
太阳下山时
By the time the sun sets,
他们就将宣誓就职  穿上警服
they will be sworn in and in uniform.
明天日出时  他们将走上街头
And by sunrise tomorrow, they will be on the streets.
那些与我们作对的人  自求多福吧
God help those who stand in our way!
抱歉  谢尔比先生
Sorry, Mr Shelby.
-谢尔比先生  -这边请
- Mr Shelby. - This way.
瞧瞧  姑娘们
You see, ladies,
跟剃刀党人出来  不用排队
when you're out with a Blinder, you don't have to queue.
好了  在他们把普通人放进来之前
Right... I want a blow job off both of you
我要你们一起来给我吹吹箫
before they let the ordinary people in.
开始吧  把帽子摘下来
Away you go. Take your hat off.
什么情况
What the fuck?!
你他妈谁啊
Who the fuck are you?!
我可是牛逼的亚瑟·谢尔比
I'm Arthur-fucking-Shelby!
亚瑟·谢尔比
Arthur Shelby.
剃刀党的领头羊
Lead pack dog of the Peaky Blinders.
看着我
Look at me.
混蛋
Bastard!
你的制服吗
Your uniform?
我明白  确实很吓人
Terrifying, I'm sure.
他有带枪吗
Did he have a gun?
没有枪  袜子里藏着把刀  腰带上有根短棍
No gun. A knife in his sock, cosh in his belt.
谢尔比先生
Now, Mr Shelby...
我希望你把这当做我对你的自我介绍
I want you to see this as me introducing myself to you.
明白吗
Understand?
在这个世界上  唯一让我感兴趣的
In all the world the only thing that interests me
只有真相
is the truth.
你对盗窃案了解多少
what do you know about the robbery?
什么盗窃案
What robbery?
我再问你一遍
I will ask you again.
你对盗窃案  了解多少
What do you know... about the robbery?
我对天发誓  我不知道你在说什么
I swear to God, I don't know what you're talking about.
他妈的什么盗窃案
What fucking robbery?
我和像你这样的畜生打了35年交道
After 35 years of dealing with animals like you,
我动动鼻子就能知道
I can tell just by sniffing the air...
你是不是在说谎
whether or not you're lying.
我他妈的没骗你  明白吗
I'm not fucking lying! All right?
我他妈的没说谎
I'm not fucking lying!
我知道
I know.
我在你通红的双眼中看不到任何可疑迹象
I see nothing of interest behind the blood in your eyes.
而且你周身的血液  都无法承载
And no blood in your veins that could carry...
任何狡诈的天分
even a trace of cunning or guile.
但你要明白
But understand this.
我手中掌握的权力
It is well within my power
足以让你和你那人渣家族
to have you and the rest of your scum family
年底之前溺死在运河里
face down in the canal before the year is out.
另一方面
On the other hand...
我们可以互相帮助
we can help each other.
白天总是这么忙吗
Is it always this busy on a daytime?
不  这些孩子要去圣安德鲁斯
No. These boys are on their way to St Andrews.
-去做祷告吗  -那是不可能的
- To pray? - That'll be the day.
圣安德鲁斯有个足球场
St Andrews is a football ground.
蓝军队在踢比赛
The Blues are playing.
那边坐着的是前锋
That's the forward line there.
信不信由你  那个人是守门员
And that's the goalie, believe it or not.
给我来瓶朗姆酒
I need a bottle of rum.
格蕾丝  无论点什么  都免费赠送
Grace, whatever it is, it's on the house.
一整瓶吗  -是的
- A whole bottle? - Yeah.
-白朗姆酒还是黑朗姆酒  -随便
- White or dark rum? - Don't care.
好的老兄  想来点什么  喝两杯吗
Right, lads, what'll it be? Two?
谢谢你
Thank you.
哈里说这是酒吧免费赠送的
Harry said it's on the house.
你是妓女吗
Are you a whore?
如果不是的话  你不该在这里
Cos if you're not, you're in the wrong place.
他就是你警告我当心的那些人之一吗
He's one of them you warned me about?
格蕾丝  你为人友善可也得多加小心
Look, Grace, you're a friendly girl but be careful.
如果我说费用全免
If I say something's on the house,
无论是谁  都别去攀谈
then say nothing to whoever you're serving.
他们要是看上你了
If they decide that they want you,
任何人都无力挽回
then there's nothing anybody could do about it.
算你幸运  自从汤米从法国回来
Lucky for you, since he got back from France,
就对女人失去了兴趣
Tommy doesn't want anybody at all.
要点什么  老兄
Yes, lads?
约翰  把他眼睛上的血擦干净
John, wipe the blood out of his eye.
什么时候轮到你发号施令了
Since when did you give orders?
我可是受过训练的护士
I'm a trained nurse.
别逗我笑  我一笑就脸疼
Don't make me laugh, it hurts me face.
我真的是啊
I bloody am!
你只去教堂上过一节急救课
You went to one first-aid class in the church hall
而且因为偷笑被赶出门外
and got thrown out for giggling.
在那之前我已经学会了如何防止人窒息
Not before I learnt how to stop somebody from choking.
我他妈的可没窒息  不是吗
I'm not bloody choking, am I?
等我把这块布缠在你脖子上  你就会了
You will be when I wrap this cloth round your neck.
让我看看他
Let me see him.
好了  喝点酒吧
All right, have this.
把那个给我
Give me that.
没事了
You're all right.
他说是丘吉尔阁下派他来伯明翰的
He said Mr. Churchill sent him to Birmingham.
他说是为了国家利益
National interest, he said.
跟盗窃案有关
Something about a robbery.
他想让我们帮他
He said he wants us to help him.
我们不帮警察
We don't help coppers.
我们在战场上的表现他全知道
He knew all about our war records.
他说我们是爱国者  和他一样
He said we're patriots... like him.
他想让我们做他的耳目
He wants us to be his eyes and ears.
我说
I said...
我说我们得开个家族会议  投票决定
I said we'd have a family meeting and take a vote.
为什么不呢
Well, why not?
我们和芬尼亚运动成员  以及共产党人都不来往
We've no truck with Fenians or Communists.
你是怎么回事
What's wrong with you?
他最近到底是怎么回事
What the fuck is wrong with him lately?!
我要是知道
If I knew,
早就从康普顿的药剂师那里买解药回来了
I'd buy the cure from Compton's Chemists.
*我只是个年轻姑娘*
*I am just a young girl*
*我从远方来*
*I have just come over*
*从那个人们做事轰轰烈烈的国家来*
*Over from the country where they do things big*
*在那些男孩之中*
*And amongst the boys*
*有我的情人*
*I've got myself a lover*
*自从有了他*
*And since I have a lover*
*我无心装扮*
*I don't care a fig*
*我的爱人在长廊中*
*The boy I love is up in the gallery*
*我的爱人注视着我*
*The boy I love is... looking at me*
*难道你们看不见他就站在那里*
*Can't you see him standing there*
*挥着他的手帕*
*Waving his handkerchief*
*像知更鸟一般快乐地在树上歌唱*
*As merry as a robin that sings on the tree*
我们从开战以来就没请人唱过歌了
We haven't had singing in here since the war.
你觉得那是为什么  哈里
Why do you think that is, Harry?
亚瑟有没有说
So did Arthur say
新警察给了他什么好处
what kind of deal this new copper offered him?
天啊  你才刚刚射完精
God! The second your balls are empty
就又开始扯政治了
it's back onto politics.
汤米怎么说
What did Tommy say?
他什么也没说
He didn't say anything.
你知道他那个德行
You know what he's like.
是啊  我知道他的品性
Yeah, I know what he's like.
他喜欢和人激烈地干一架
He likes to take his fights onto the mud.
不喜欢站着等待
Doesn't like to stand and wait.
你知道他要是发现我们的事会怎么做
You know what he'd do if he found out about us.
他尽管放马过来
He could try.
有时候我觉得  你和我在一起
Sometimes, it's like you're with me
只是为了证明你能和我在一起
just to show you can.
总有一天我和汤米会再次站在同一阵营的
One day me and Tommy will be on the same side again.
汤米
Tommy...!
你干什么呢  我们关门了  回家去
Hey, what you do? We're closed. Go home.
回家去  疯子
Go home, crazy man.
我叫你回家去呢  疯子
I said go home, crazy man!
我说了回家去
I said go home.
小心刺刀
Fix bayonets!!!
国务大臣  这位是总督察坎贝尔
Secretary of State, this is Chief Inspector Campbell.
丘吉尔阁下  长官
Mr Churchill, sir,
能得到您的召见我无比荣耀
may I say what a great honour it is to meet you.
短暂停留而已
Bit of a whistle stop tour.
-对了  你的帽子不错  -谢谢您
- Love the hat, by the way. - Thank you.
是海狸皮的
It's beaver.
那么  你来到这里的适应情况如何
So, how are you settling in?
我成立了一个指挥网络
I have set up a command network.
我在全城都安插了内线
I have agents in place across the city
充当我的耳目
who will act as my eyes and ears.
同时加大审讯嫌犯的力度
And I have begun to interrogate suspects vigorously.
你在贝尔法斯特待过
You were in Belfast.
我知道你让一些芬尼亚分子心碎
I understand you broke a few Fenian hearts.
老鼠窝罢了  阁下
A rat's nest, sir.
你觉得枪是谁偷的
So who do you think stole the guns?
芬尼亚成员还是共产主义分子
Fenians or Communists?
如果是爱尔兰共和军干的
If it is IRA Fenians,
我会找到他们  夺回枪支
I will find them and find the guns.
如果是共产主义分子  我会找到他们夺回枪支
If it is Communists, I will find them and find the guns.
如果是普通的罪犯  我也会找到他们夺回枪支
If it is common criminals, I will find them and find the guns.
对我来说  嫌犯是谁都没有差别
To me there are no distinction between any of the above.
我们选你就是因为你做事很有成效
We chose you because you are effective.
但你记住一点  坎贝尔先生
But remember this, Mr Campbell.
这里是英国  不是贝尔法斯特
This is England, not Belfast.
尸体扔进河里  最终也会被登上报纸
Bodies thrown in the rivers, wash up in the papers here.
我们绝不能让新闻报道那些被偷的枪支
We must keep the existence of these stolen guns out of the news
否则无异于是在为那些枪打广告找买家了
otherwise we will simply be advertising them for sale.
如果真要弄死一些人
If there are bodies to be buried,
就挖洞深埋起来  要干净利落
dig holes and dig them deep.
我希望一切都要找回  一粒子弹都不能放过
I want everything accounted for down to the last bullet.
查理叔叔  跟你说句话
Uncle Charlie, a word.
那些都搬上船了  今晚没有月亮
They are aboard. There's no moon.
我们可以把这些送到格斯街那边的拐弯处
We can take them out to the turning point beyond Gas Street
然后丢弃在河岸上
and leave them on the bank.
它们很快就会被铁路工人发现
They'll be found by railway men first thing.
那是大家都同意的做法吗
Is that agreement?
我改变主意了
I changed my mind.
你什么
You what?
我还有一个备选方案
I have an alternative strategy.
让科利把船开到老烟草码头
Tell Curly to take her out to the old tobacco wharf.
那里有个停泊场  是我们以前用来存放香烟的
There's a lock up mooring we used to keep cigarettes.
他知道在哪儿
He knows it.
船离开了你的范围  你就不必担心了
When the boat leaves your yard, it's no longer your concern.
你他妈的是疯了吗
Have you lost your fucking mind?
你没看见街上的情况吗
Have you not seen the streets?
他们派了一支军队过来寻找这些枪支
They've sent a fucking army to find these things...
你说的对  他们已经显露了意图
That's right. They've shown their hand...
显露意图
Their hand?
如果他们这么急切地想找回枪支
If they want them back this bad,
他们就得付出代价
they'll have to pay.
世道就是这样的
That's the way of the world.
命运把价值无限的宝贝送到你面前
Fortune drops something valuable in your lap,
你可不能白白就扔了出去
you don't just dump it on the bank of the cut.
你是我的亲人  汤米
You're blood, Tommy.
我一直像个父亲一样照顾你
I've always looked out for you like a dad.
你会招来大祸临头的
You're going to bring holy hell down on your head.
那个警察可不会留俘虏
This copper takes no prisoners.
我听说他都没服过役
I'm told he didn't serve.
他从事的是免服兵役的职业
Reserved occupation.
你想引发另一场战争吗  汤米
Is it another war you're looking for, Tommy?
烟草码头
The tobacco wharf.
剃刀党命令你这样做
By order of the Peaky Blinders.
你打入进去了吗
Are you in position?
是的  先生
I am, sir.
你的第一印象是什么
Your first impressions?
我对那些人的生活感到震惊
I am quite shocked at how these people live.
你搞到对我有用的信息了吗
Have you found anything out that might help me?
我审讯了剃刀党的头目
I interrogated the head of the Peaky Blinders.
他什么都不知道
He didn't know anything.
一个畜生
A brute.
我突然想到掌控谢尔比家族的不是亚瑟
It strikes me that it isn't Arthur who heads the Shelby family.
是年轻的那个  汤玛斯
It is the younger one, Thomas.
人们都说他在战场上获得过两枚英勇勋章
They say he won two medals for gallantry in the war.
你听上去似乎很迷恋他
You sound fascinated.
不过  我的想法还是没有变
However, my opinion has not changed.
那些经营赌马的黑帮有其他业务
The bookmaker gangs have other business
而共产主义分子又太弱  不可能谋划此案
and the Communists are too weak to have planned this.
我相信那些枪是被爱尔兰共和军劫走了
I believe the guns were taken by the IRA.
你不能让你个人的历史经历影响你的判断
You must not let your personal history cloud your judgment.
什么历史经历
What history?
爱尔兰共和军谋害了我父亲一事
That the IRA murdered my father
不会影响我的判断
will not affect my judgment.
如果你看到任何一把枪
If you see any guns,
就对比一下这张单子上的序列号
check the serial numbers against that list.
你父亲
Your father
是我曾共事过的最优秀的警官
was the finest officer I ever worked with.
我知道他一定会为你非常非常骄傲的
I know he would be very, very proud of you.
丹尼  你杀的那个人是意大利人
Danny, as you know, the man you killed was Italian.
那边那两个人是他兄弟
And those two men over there are his brothers.
如果我同意意大利人的处理方法  丹尼
If I let the Italians do this, Danny,
他们就会切掉你的生殖器  让你血尽而亡
they'll cut off your manhood and let you drain.
那些混蛋就是这么做事的
That's how those bastards do things.
所以  为了阻止我们和意大利人间发生争战
So, to stop a war breaking out between us and the Italians...
也让你不受他们野蛮行为的虐待
and to save you from their barbarity...
我说我会亲自送你上路
I said I would dispatch you myself.
他们是来做见证的
They are here to witness.
我其实早就死在战场上了  汤米
I died over there anyway, Tommy.
我的大脑早已埋进了那些淤泥里
I left my fucking brains in the mud.
你还有什么遗愿吗  兄弟
You have any last requests, comrade?
你会帮我照看罗丝和孩子们的吧
You'll look out for my Rosie and my boys?
一定要让他们当上学徒
See they get apprenticeships.
在轻兵器工厂或奥斯丁汽车公司都行
At the BSA factory or the Austin.
他们会成为工头的  我知道他们会的
They'll make foremen. I know they will.
就是普通的
Just ordinary...
就是普通人
Just ordinary men.
他们不必做那些残酷的
And they won't get told to do this shit...
我们做过的那些  残酷恶心的事
This shit... This shit that we got told to do.
我觉得我现在该祈祷了
I suppose I ought to pray now.
那些该死的枪  让上帝彻底从我的脑海中消失
Those fucking guns blew God right out of my head.
那只船是为我准备的吗
Is that boat for me?
我们必须把你的尸体运出城  丹尼
We have to get your body out of the city, Danny.
那个新来的警察  你知道的
This new copper, you know...
不要把我埋在有淤泥的地方  好吗
Don't bury me anywhere where there's mud. OK?
答应我
Promise me.
把我埋在山上  告诉罗丝地点
Bury me on a hill and tell Rosie where.
你曾是个好人  也是个优秀的士兵
You were a good man and a good soldier.
是  军士长
Yes, Sergeant Major.
在凄凉的冬至日
In the bleak midwinter.
你去哪儿了
Where are you?
它竟然获胜了
It bloody won!
摩纳根小子竟然他妈的获胜了
Monaghan Boy bloody won!
是啊  它获胜了
Yeah. It won.
消息会传开来
And word will spread.
所以下次我们再施展红粉巫术时
So next time we do the powder trick
不仅是加里森地区的人会押那匹马
it won't just be The Garrison that'll bet on the horse,
整个小希斯地区的人都会押它
it'll be the whole of Small Heath.
你知道吗  那匹马还会再赢的
And you know what? The horse will win again.
第三次我们就下手
And the third time we do it
我们让整个伯明翰的人都押它
we'll have the whole of Birmingham betting on it.
一千英镑的钱押在那匹被施了魔法的马上
A thousand quid bet on the magic horse.
到时候
And that time,
等我们准备好  那匹马就会输
when we are ready, the horse will lose.
好好想想吧
Think about it.
你没事吧  丹尼
You OK, Danny?
我还是惊魂未定
I'm still in shock.
你确定这不是天堂吗
You sure this isn't heaven?
如果这是天堂  我怎么会在天堂呢
If it was heaven, what would I be doing here?
汤米希望让你觉得那是真的
Tommy wanted you to think it was real
想借此刺激你恢复理智
to try and knock some sense into you.
打在一袋羊脑上还是挺疼的
A shell full of sheep brains hurts pretty bad.
就该疼才对嘛
It was meant to.
-你要载我去哪儿  -伦敦
- So where are you taking me? - London.
汤米有个小任务让你完成
Tommy has a little job for you.
给你一个表达谢意的机会
Give you chance to say thanks.
你现在是剃刀党的一员了  丹尼
You're a Peaky Blinder now, Danny.
真是糟糕的一周
A bad week.
昨晚没有月亮  我查过了
There was no moon last night. I checked.
你做出了正确的选择吗
Did you do the right thing?
是的  我做了正确的选择
Yes, I did the right thing.